Derek Mackley

Staff Product Security Engineer Warrior, AL 32951 · (770) 402-6341 Derek.Mackley@hotmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/DMackley https://github.com/DapperDivers

SUMMARY

Disciplined and ambitious BSA Eagle Scout who sets and achieves goals. This correlates with my track record of releasing quality software on time, with teams of all sizes, and budgets. I've worked in a variety of industries with multiple tech stacks and am very passionate about Cybersecurity and lifelong learning.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Management Skills: Effectively take business requirements and then plan, schedule, and release quality software. Interviewing, hiring, and building effective teams. Strategic planning for business requirements balanced with technical debt, and modernization.
- Programming Proficiencies: .NET, C#, SQL, MVC, Webforms, AngualarJS, Angular, React, NPM, JavaScript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Visual Studio, Microsoft Azure, LINQ, Entity Framework, PHP, Laravel, Python, Flask, Mosquito MQTT, EMQX, Tera Term, Linux development, Ansible, Azure Devops, Jenkins, Git, Docker, Proxmox, AWS, Google Cloud, Azure, Kubernetes, Helm, NestJS, Reloader, ArgoCD, Trivy, Github Actions, Flux, ArgoCD, Talos, k8s
- Certifications: Practical Network Penetration Tester (PNPT), AINS 21, Google Cybersecurity

EXPERIENCE

Mastery Logistics Systems

Remote

Staff Product Security Engineer

July 2023 – Present

- Working as the technical lead of a newly formed product security team. While in this role, it's been the goal to create a vulnerability management program for the organization. This has included aggregation of vulnerabilities in our environment with the use of both closed and open-source tools and then building Power BI dashboards to display this information. Armed with that information, the next step was to categorize these vulnerabilities in a way that showcases risk to the business. After this, documentation was created to explain the vulnerabilities found and provide the steps needed to resolve and remove the riskiest findings from our environment. Finally showing how to exploit the riskiest vulnerabilities with active enumeration in our test environment.
- The second phase of this program is to create automations and processes to shift-left as much as humanly possible. This has been done by creating a suite of GitHub actions that check each pull request for secrets, vulnerable packages, and out of date base images.
- The final phase of the program is to aggregate findings, associate them to teams, and then track remediation. I have been able to get the first two parts of this completed by writing a custom tool to associate Kubernetes resources to GitHub repos, and then to the people and regions that those are associated to. This gives me the ability to run scans on the resources in the organization and then (soon) be able to automatically create Jira tickets with SLA's and track that the findings are mitigated.

Senor Software Engineering Manager

May 2022 – July 2023

• Worked as the Senior Software Engineering Manager in the International region at Mastery Logistics Systems. In this role I led my teams to successfully complete projects including integrations with ITS, Slack, Teams, an IMDL aggregation tool, and a "flat-file" integration that is being used by multiple domains. While in this role I led as many as 9 teams and have helped to define the SDLC for the international region. This role required the ability to juggle many projects simultaneously as well as facilitate communication between many technical and non-technical team members. While in this role my responsibilities included very hands on technical work to resolve bugs or solve deployment issues, to large scale project planning with multiple teams.

Traction Tools Remote

Software Engineering Manager

February 2021 - May 2022

• Worked as the Software Engineering Manager for a direct-to-consumer site that provides tooling for businesses running EOS. I led the software, QA, and project management teams, overseeing sprint management, code

reviews, tech stack, and the direction of the product from an engineering standpoint. While in this role I instituted Azure Devops, automated deployments, unit testing, integration testing, selenium tests and a two-week sprint/release cadence to the organization. I led the effort to modernize the tech stack, by methodically migrating the website from .NET 4.6.1 MVC Razor and AngularJS, to a microservices architecture with a react front end. This involved moving from AWS virtual machines to an ECS cluster, as well as migrating the current project to .NET Core while ensuring no downtime and adding new features. Basically, rebuilding the car piece by piece while in a drag race.

Satcom Direct (Contract)

Melbourne, Fl

Senior Software Engineer

July 2020 - February 2021

• Contract role working with a large array of microservices written in .NET C#. This includes some Azure functions as well as windows forms apps, MVC applications, .NET API's, an Angular 7 portal, and many others. The purpose of all of this is to receive, manipulate, and enhance messages from planes and then send them back to the pilot in real time. Most of the development in this position was "high risk" as any mistakes made could force a plane to land. This creates the need for high coverage of unit and integration tests, with architecture planned around high availability.

Ubicquia Melbourne, Fl

Senior Software Engineer / Development Lead

February 2019 - June 2020

• At this startup, I learned an incredible amount and overcame unique challenges on a day-to-day basis. This role involved creating an enterprise solution to manage cellular connected units on light poles. While in this role, I wrote and managed a PHP Laravel API, with an Angular front end, as well as wrote automation frameworks, MQTT broker connections, python API's, virtualized environments, and a whole host of supporting software. I also learned to manage and configure Linux environments and wrote Ansible scripts to migrate and re-architect the business from Azure to the Google Cloud Platform. The last one saving the company 500K annually. This role involved managing a small team (myself in the back end, 2 people in the FE, and 1 in QA) with big tasks, and short deadlines. This taught me to move quickly, focus on what is truly important, and to write extensible software with manageable tech debt.

Medicomp Inc Melbourne, FI

Senior Software Developer / Development Lead

May 2018 – February 2019

• While at Medicomp I primarily worked on their direct-to-consumer website AAW that displays reports to doctors nationally. The site was written in webforms and jQuery the challenge being to implement new features and using standard best practices while supporting legacy code. This includes creating new features to use primarily web methods, as well as rewriting pieces of the application in order to facilitate a move to a more modern architecture. I managed a team of four to prioritize work and ensure quality. Before this project I was on a team that attempted to fix an outsourced MVC 5, knockout.js application hosted in Azure that analyzed and diagnosed patient's ECG data.

Starr Companies Atlanta, GA

Application Developer

August 2017 - May 2018

• Worked on a Document Management/ Reporting web portal. Myself and one other developer rewrote the site in MVC 5 from webforms, moved from an on-prem virtual machine to an azure web service, moved our most resource intensive page to Angular JS, and at the time I left were in the process of updating the front-end to use modern technologies, like Saas, Twitter Bootstrap, NodeJS, etc. In addition, began moving the service layer from .NET4.6.1 to a .NET Core Web API.

Global Associate/IT Associate

March 2016 – August 2017

• As part of the Global Associates program at Starr Companies, I was given the unique opportunity to speak and learn from Industry leaders in order to get a comprehensive knowledge of the Property and Casualty side of the Insurance industry. This included creating multiple POC's most notably a cross selling utility that allowed

underwriters to see if other facets of Starr were doing business with the same client. In addition to my studies while in this program, I worked as a developer for the duration of this time on the project listed in the description above, and during this time took the daily user base of 30 underwriters to more than 250 across many facets of Starr.

Astreya Atlanta, GA

Equipment Management Technician

Nov 2015 - March 2016

• Managed Google's asset inventory system for the Atlanta area and parts of the Southeast, imaged and deployed hardware, and ensured conferencing offices were operational are running smoothly.

Sunshine Divers Koh Tao, Thailand

PADI Divemaster

March 2015 – August 2015

- Used management and organizational skills to run a dive training facility.
- Sold, coordinated, and assisted with dive courses.
- Managed customer expectations and ensured safe practices in accordance with insurance regulations.

EDUCATION

Georgia State University, J. Mack Robinson College of Business

Atlanta, GA

Bachelor of Business Administration, Computer Information Systems

January 2015

Minor: Information Security

PERSONAL DEVELOPMENT

- HomeLab: Running a Proxmox cluster that hosts ~30 docker containers and 180TB of storage.
- Electrical Engineering: RFID remote car start prototype, Custom keyboard
- Mechanical Engineering: Four 3D printers, Fusion 360, assortment of slicer software
- PADI Divemaster